玄黄端现 太极混沌如鸡蛋
ln the beginning, there was darkness...
随着轰的一声
and then, bang...
诞生了无限膨胀的时间 空间和物质
giving birth to an endless expanding existence...of time, space, and matter.
现在 所见超乎我们的想像
Now, see further than we've ever imagined...
超越了客观认知极限
beyond the limits of our existence...
那地方我们称之为"宇宙"
in a place we call "The Universe".
科技所提出的承诺
lt promises to deliver technologies...
是我们的旅行将更遥远 更快捷
that will carry us everfarther and everfaster.
然而始终充满着致命的危险
But it's fraught with constant and lethal peril.
在外太空飞行宛如穿行射击场
Flying in outer space is like going through a shooting gallery.
将考验人类的能力与智慧的极限
lt will test the limits of human capacity and human ingenuity.
如果出错了 你将怎么办？
lf something goes wrong, what do you do?
无能为力 只好坐以待毙
Nothing. You just die.
欢迎来到太空旅行时代
Welcome to the age of space travel.
--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制:春树  字幕来源:五羊皮  调校:御雪寒狼  招募Q号:76846146
[历史频道] 第二季 第八集 太空旅行
[History Channel] The UniverseⅡ 08of19 Space.Travel
以几乎不曾想过的方式 以平稳的上进之手
ln ways scarcely even imagined, the steady hand of progress...
平稳地将人类送上天空
is poised to deliver humanity to the heavens.
多少年来 神秘辉煌的宇宙
For ages, the mysterious splendor of the universe...
从其遥远的高处引诱着我们
has enticed us from its remote heights.
终于 其神秘的诱惑已触手可及了
At last, its mysterious temptations are within reach...
人类的命运可以实现了
and man's destiny can be fulfilled.
我不知道我们基因里的命令
l don't know if it's writ in our genes...
但是一旦你看到远处的东西
but anytime you see something at a distance...
它激起了你的好奇心
and it piques your curiosity...
你立马想要做的事就是凑近看看
the first thing you want to do is get a closer look.
因此 望远镜在这一点上让你看得够远了
So, while telescopes get you pretty far in this regard...
那些东西已经近到
those things that are sort of close enough...
我们的太空计划已触手可及了
to be within the reach of our space program...
此时 为何不去旅行一番呢？
why not take the trip?
倒计时十 九…
T-minus ten, nine...
主发动机点火
main engine start.
五 四 亚特兰大号升空
Five, four, and lift-off of Space Shuttle "Atlantis".
窥视摆脱地球的控制
Prying free from our home planet's grip...
跻身人类最伟大的成就
ranks among the greatest of human achievements.
然而 1972年以来 尚无人大胆超越地球的轨道
But no one since 1972 has ventured beyond the Earth's orbit.
我们的太空计划已经卡住了30年了
Our space program has been stuck for thirty years.
我们只是围绕着地球转
We simply just go around the planet Earth.
这就像哥伦布首次发现新大陆后
lt's just like Columbus exploring the New world for the first time...
余生就消磨在西班牙海岸边游荡
and then spending the rest of his life..simply puttering around the Spanish coastline.
问题出在哪里？
What's the problem?
出在肮脏的两个字上 "开销"
There's a dirty little four-letterword...and that is "cost".
将一磅东西送入轨道的成本约1万美元
lt costs about $10,000 to put a pound of anything into orbit.
想不到约翰·格列(宇航员)是纯金打造的
lmagine John Glenn made out of solid gold.
那就是将约翰·格列或你送入轨道的代价
That's what it costs to put John Glenn or you into orbit.
将花费2000万美元
lt would cost about $20 million...
把你送去太空站作周末游
for you to take a weekend trip up to the Space Station.
将花费5亿美元把你送上月球
lt would cost about a half a billion dollars...for you to go to the Moon.
而你要去火星的话
And for you to go to Mars...
或许要花上数百亿美元才行
would probably cost tens of billions of dollars.
缩减太空旅行开支的方法之一
One way to reduce the cost of reaching space...
就是找到克服地球引力更有效的办法
would be to find a more efficient way to overcome Earth's gravity.
记得《杰克与魔豆》的故事吗？
Remember the story of Jack and the Beanstalk?
杰克就是那个攀爬着魔豆上天的小男孩
Jack was a little boy who climbed the beanstalk into heaven.
啊 想像一下有一架太空电梯 你按一下按钮"上"
Well, imagine a space elevator such that you hit the "up" button...
电梯就带你上天
and the elevator takes you into the heavens...
就像杰克与魔豆那样
just like Jack and the Beanstalk.
不是从下往上建造
lnstead of building from the ground up...
太空电梯是自上而下建造的
the space elevatorwould be built from the top down.
同步轨道卫星
A satellite in geosynchronous orbit...
放下一根6万英里的缆绳到地球
would drop a 60,000-mile cable back to Earth...
它将被锚固在地面上
where it would be anchored to the surface.
现在我们已经接近于有能力创造出纤维
Now we are within striking distance of being able to create fibers...
来承受太空电梯在地球轨道上
that can with stand the tension...
以超高速上下移动所产生的张力
of traveling at enormous velocities in outer space...as the space elevator rotates with the planet Earth.
它永远不会掉下来是因为它的运转速度
So it never falls because it rotates...
等同于地球的速度
at the same rate as the planet Earth.
电梯的轿厢沿着缆绳盘旋而上
The elevator's compartment would simply roll up the cable...
将乘客和补给送上轨道
shuttling travelers and supplies into orbit...
在那里等候飞船
where it would wait for a spacecraft.
这一系统将完全取代传统的火箭发射
This system would entirely replace a conventional rocket launch.
那有可能减少太空旅行的开销1000倍
And that might reduce the cost of space travel...by a factor of a thousand.
试想一下
Think about that.
接着你开始意识到或许外太空之旅
Then you begin to realize that perhaps a trip to outer space...
可能不比飞机票差多少
may be no worse than an airplane ticket.
然而 超越了地球亲切拥抱的界限
But beyond the limits of Earth's comforting embrace...
外部的威胁在等待着每一位太空游客
exotic menaces await every space traveler.
飞行在外太空
Flying in outer space...
就不像在陆地上开车畅游了
is not like taking a nice ride in the country in a car.
就像是穿行在射击场里
lt's like going through a shooting gallery.
对于一个不知情的游客来说
To an unsuspecting voyager...
就似乎是宇宙在举枪瞄准一样
it might seem the universe is taking aim with a firearm.
太空中存在着粒子
There are particles in space...
甚至灰尘大小的颗粒 如卵石大小的颗粒
even dust-sized particles, pebble-sized particles...
其时速达到了数万英里
that are traveling tens of thousands of miles an hour...
有时甚至更快
and sometimes even faster.
50多万的弹丸直径超过了一英吋
More than half a million of these projectiles...measuring over an inch in diameter...
现在正在我们地球周围呼啸而过
are zipping around our planet right now.
其中包括太阳能电池的玻璃碎片
They include pieces of glass broken off of solar cells...
航天器的装饰碎片
paint chips from spacecraft...
以及火箭助推器的碎片
and debris from rocket booster engines.
到了深太空会有更大的危险
And in deeper space, there's more danger...
来自卵石般大小的流星叫做微流星体
from pebble-sized meteors called micrometeoroids.
一小粒尘埃可以击碎玻璃 洞穿金属
A small piece of dust can crack glass, it can penetrate metal...
可以粉碎塑料
it can pulverize plastic.
那就是太空中始终出现的情况
And that does happen in space all the time.
或许还有更致命的危险
But perhaps an even more deadly danger...
根本不是固体 潜伏在那里:辐射
not at all solid, lies in wait: Radiation.
这个无形能量的破坏力
The devastating effects of this invisible energy...
已经在地球上目睹过
have been witnessed on Earth...
二战期间的原子弹的后果
in the aftermath of the atomic bombs of world War ll...
切尔诺贝利的核尘埃
and the nuclearfallout of Chernobyl.
令人不安的是维持我们生命的太阳
Distressingly, our own life-giving Sun...
在喷发出有害的辐射
spews out streams of poisonous radiation.
因此要意识到我们一直得到这个摇篮的呵护
So realize that we've been protected in this cradle.
我们受到了地球大气层的保护
We've been protected by the atmosphere of the Earth.
地球磁场吞噬了
The magnetic field of the Earth gobbles up...
太阳发出的耀斑并创造了北极光
most of the flares from the Sun to create the Aurora Borealis.
在太空里你可以看到北极光迎面而来
ln outer space, you get the Aurora Borealis coming right at you.
没有臭氧层
There's no ozone layer...
没有磁场来保护你
there's no magnetic field to protect you.
就是你和外太空的恶劣环境
lt's just you and the harshness of outer space.
我们地球与太阳的距离
At our home planet's distance from the Sun...
大约9000万英里
roughly ninety million miles away...
在地球的周围每秒钟每平方英吋的太空中
several hundred million solar particles...
有几亿个太阳粒子穿过
pass through each square inch of space...every second around our Earth.
这些都是太阳一刻不停流出的高能粒子
There's high-energy particles streaming from the Sun all the time.
然而有时
But every now and then...
会有一次这些粒子的超大剂量
there's an extra dose of these particles.
太阳打嗝吐出高能辐射
The Sun burps up high-energy radiation.
那也不好
That's bad, too.
这种辐射水平对人的DNA没什么好处
That level of radiation it is never good for one's DNA.
太阳黑子爆发出这些超量的能量
Sunspots flare up these extra doses of energy...
就像宇宙大炮的连续轰击
like a battery of cannons bombarding the cosmos.
在其抵达前根本无法获知其行径
There's no way to know that they're going to be here...before they arrive.
不幸的是 还是存在着辐射的危险
Unfortunately, there's still a risk of radiation...
尽管我们远离了太阳
even as we get farther from the Sun.
那是因为还有一个危险的能量潜伏着
That's because another invading energy lurks.
所谓的银河宇宙射线
Known as galactic cosmic rays...
它们来自遥远的外部世界的
they hail from the distant alien worlds...
恒星爆炸和黑洞
of exploding stars and black holes.
银河宇宙射线是以近乎光速穿行的粒子
Galactic cosmic rays are particles that are traveling at speeds...very close to the speed of light.
即使是一个铁粒子撞进你的身体
Even a single particle of iron slamming into your body...
都会具有职业棒球的效果
can have the effect of a Major League baseball...
时速上百英里
at a hundred miles an hour.
具有毁灭性
They can be devastating.
尽管沉重的铁粒子相当罕见
Although heavy iron particles are rare...
但是置身航天器保护之外
outside of the protection of a spacecraft...
诸如宇航员在舱外漫步时
such as when an astronaut performs a spacewalk...
每秒钟会有数以千计的银河宇宙射线
thousands of galactic cosmic rays...
穿过你的身体
do penetrate the body every second.
每昼夜银河宇宙射线和太阳粒子
Every 24 hours, the galactic cosmic rays and solar particles...
攻击太空游客带来的辐射
attack a space traveler with as much radiation...
相当于地球居民六个月里所接受的量
as a surface dweller on Earth receives in six months.
人体不会马上感觉到辐射的影响
The human body won't immediately feel the impacting radiation...
但是到了一定的量就可以觉察到了
but in sufficient quantities, it can be noticed.
即使闭上眼睛 粒子也会金星闪烁
Even with eyes closed, the particles spark flashes...
此时它们在轰击太空游客的视网膜
when they strike a space traveler's retina.
闪烁不会致盲 但你不得不问自己
The flashes are not blinding, and you have to ask yourself,
啊 我都看到了什么？
"Hmm, did l see something"?
然后你会说:"噢 看到了"
And then you say, "Oh, yes, l did".
然后其模样时不时有所差异
And then its appearances are a little different from time to time.
不管怎样 人体确实感觉到了
However, the human body does feel the shock...
这种奇特的失重经历的震惊
of this bizarre weightless existence.
我认为进入太空最危险的情况
l think that the most dangerous thing going into space...
就是失重
is the loss of gravity.
失重会引起你身体几乎每个系统都
Weightlessness causes almost every system in your body...
开始变化 变化不会停止
to start changing, and it doesn't stop changing...
除非你再次回到有重力的世界
until you get back onto a world...where you're pulled down again by its gravity.
零重力的第一批受害者之一
One of the first casualties of zero gravity...
就是太空游客的方向感
is a space traveler's sense of direction.
上下方向在哪？
What's up and what's down?
很好的问题
Very good question.
不管怎样 这是你首先要弄明白的
And first of all, it's whatever you want it to be.
如果你认为这是上 那非常好
lf you want this to be up, that's fine...
而你认为这是上 那还算过的去
but If you want this to be up, that's just as good.
多数游客会患上晕动病
Most travelers will suffer from motion sickness...
在开头的几个小时甚者几天
for the first few hours or, most likely, days.
这是避免不了的
lt's just one of those things...
你只得听天由命
that you ought to resign yourself to facing...
每个人都极有可能感觉到方向感有一点混乱
that everyone is very likely to feel a little bit disturbed...in terms of orientation.
在地球上水肺潜水员飘浮在水下
Here on Earth, scuba divers floating underwater...
体验到长时间无重力最接近的感受
experience the nearest sensation of prolonged periods without gravity.
正是出于这个原因有志成为宇航员的人
lt is for this very reason that aspiring NASA astronauts...
要在无重力的环境中训练生活和工作
train to live and work in a gravity-free environment...
通过将他们自己一次六个小时
by subjecting themselves for up to six hours at a time...
放在一个大水罐里
in a large water tank.
现在水下呼吸器 你还是能感受到重力
Now, scuba equipment, you still experience the forces of gravity...
但是它感觉不出来 因为你整个身子
but it doesn't feel like it because your whole body...
被水均匀地托起 将你浮起来
is uniformly buoyed by the water that holds you up.
除了可以看到表面漂起的水泡
And except for the visual cue of air bubbles floating to the surface...
在水下游泳可以模拟失去方向的感觉
swimming underwater can mimic the sensation of disorientation.
但是随着时间的流逝在失重的太空中
But, as time passes in the weightlessness of space...
人体感觉到已无需抵抗重力了
the human body senses it no longer needs to resist the force of gravity...
肌肉骨质就开始流失了
and begins shedding muscle and bone mass.
你身处太空中
When you're in space...
你的身体会认为你可能还在床上睡觉呢
your body thinks you might as well be lying in bed.
所以要是你不加留意的话你的身体就会萎缩
And so If you're not careful, your body will atrophy.
为了抗衡此作用每天在太空中
To counter this, each day in space...
宇航员都必须进行锻炼
an astronaut needs to exercise.
因为很少使用腿 所以腿特别容易受伤
The legs are especially vulnerable because they are seldom used.
在这个天地里双臂双手在搬动身体中
ln this world, the arms and hands do most of the work...
劳动强度最大
to move the body around.
经常要碰到的最困难的事情
What would be the toughest thing to get used to...
很可能就是你生活在太空中
might very well be just how you live in space...
不能在房间里走动
where you can't walk across the room.
你必须漂移到你要去的地方
You have to float everywhere you're going.
失重也会减缓消化功能
The lack of gravity also slows down the digestive tract...
这就会引起进餐的问题
which can cause problems at mealtime.
你的消化系统会停摆
Your digestive system stops.
你不能吃 不能喝
You can't eat, you can't drink...
直到你重新开始消化为止
until you can start digesting again.
那无论如何都可能会耽误上几个小时到几天工夫
And that can take anywhere from hours to days.
更为糟糕的是失重与辐射会以
Worse still, zero gravity and radiation can combine...
一个特别危险的方式结合在一起
in an especially sinisterway.
太空中免疫系统不会如平常那个那样有效
ln space, the immune system is not as effective as it normally is.
我们平常能够承受的许多细菌和病毒
And many of the bacteria and viruses...
变得愈加危险
that we normally can withstand become more virulent.
加上细菌的繁殖可能会快上50倍
Additionally, bacteria can grow up to fifty times faster...
带上去的病毒 可能会变异成前所未有的杀手
and any virus brought onboard...could mutate into a never-before-seen predator...
祸根在于无处不在的辐射
thanks to the ever-present radiation.
所有这些困难折磨着太空游客
All these difficulties prey on space travelers...
在最先的几个小时乃至几天里
in just the first few hours or days.
长时间的旅游又如何呢？
And what aboutjourneys that need more time?
只会变得愈加艰难
lt only gets tougher.
宇宙是个无情的地方
The universe is an unforgiving place.
它只开放给最大胆的冒险家
lt's open to only the boldest adventurers...
他们具有勇往直前的勇气
those who have the mettle to trek deep...
深入充满危险的环境之中
into an environment swimming with toxic hazards...
不畏艰险远离安全熟悉的地方
and unafraid to stray far from the safe and familiar.
我们视为理所当然的 穿着轻便
We take it for granted that clothing is flexible...
在室温中作业
and machines work in room temperature...
因为或明或暗 本来就应该这样的
because, implicitly or explicitly, they're designed for that.
你进入了深太空 要是你面对太阳
You go into the depths of space, If you're facing the Sun...
温度就可能达到数百华氏度
it could be hundreds of degrees Fahrenheit.
要是你背离太阳
lf you're facing away from the Sun...
就可能是零下几百度
it could be hundreds of degrees below zero.
在地球上有很多你都视为理所当然的
Down here on Earth, you take so much for granted.
你知道我们在户外
You know, we're out here...
阳光 新鲜空气都包围着你
the sunshine, the fresh air all around you.
在那里你就处在一个封闭的生态系统里了
Up there, you're in a closed ecosystem.
你必须提供所有的人类必需品
You have to supply all the human needs...
在地球上 会自动照应我们的
that the Earth just, you know, automatically does for us.
你不得不指望 整个船停靠在一起
You have to hope that the integrity of the hull...
这样你就不会快速减压 很快窒息
stays together so you don't have rapid decompression...quick suffocation.
同样的现实也存在于在海洋深处游荡的潜艇
The same reality exists for a submarine...liding deep through the ocean.
它提供了一个生命保护屏障来保护其居民
lt provides a life-preserving barrier to protect its inhabitants...
免受周围的外部世界的威胁
from a surrounding alien world.
假如飞船损坏 空气就会泄漏 你就会玩儿完
lf there's damage to the spaceship, air leaks out, you die.
潜艇损坏 水会进入 你也会玩儿完
Damage to submarine, water gets in, you die.
所以 孤独 生理和个人
So the isolation, both physically and personally...
两者之间似乎相当类似
between the two seems quite parallel.
潜在的灾难性事故潜伏着
The potential for a catastrophic mishap lurks.
当你身处海洋深处
When you're out in the middle of the ocean...
你只有自己和同伴可以依靠
you have only yourself and your colleagues to rely on...
太空中的情况也是一样的
and the same thing applies in space.
一切都必须承受得住
Things have to hold up.
你不可能回家
You can't come back.
你不可能跑去五金商店
You can't run to the hardware store.
你不可能用某些没带来的部件来修理东西
You can't fix the thing with some part that you didn't bring along.
你只能利用人类智慧
And you're stuck with human ingenuity...
这你随身携带的工具
the tools you brought with you.
到了外太空
And out there in space...
你真的远离了人类
you truly are just removed from mankind.
这种孤独是我以前从未体会过的
lt is isolation like l've neverfelt before.
升空 我们已经升空
Lift off, we have lift off...
通常我们探索太空的努力一直比喻为
Often our efforts to explore space have been analogized...
15 16世纪的伟大的探险家
to the great explorers of the 15th and 16th century...
首次越洋发现新大陆
the first to cross the oceans, going to unknown territory...
带上所有的补给
having to bring all their supplies with them...
不知道他们是否还会回来
not knowing if they'll ever return.
我想对那种比喻有很多话要说
And l think there's a lot to say about that analogy.
然而 有一点是不堪一击的
But there's a point where it breaks down badly.
国会号登陆南美时
When Cortes landed in South America...
哥伦布抵达加勒比时
when Columbus hit the Caribbean...
不是还有空气让他呼吸吗？
there was still air there for him to breathe, all right?
树上长着水果
There was fruit on the trees.
设想一下阿波罗11号宇航员 阿姆斯特朗和奥尔德林
Suppose the Apollo 11 astronauts, Neil Armstrong and BuzzAldrin...
登陆月球 比如发动机坏了
landed on the Moon and, like, the engine broke.
好 休斯顿 我们现在出现了问题
Okay, Houston, we've had a problem here.
你能做什么？
What do you do?
束手无策 只是等死
Nothing. You just die.
没有那种发动机树
There's not sort of an engine tree...
供他们选择部件来修理飞船
that they can pluck parts from to repair their ship.
因此 在太空探索中对人类健康的危险远大于
So the hazards are vastly greater to human health...
在地球表面的各地旅行
in space exploration than traveling anywhere on Earth's surface.
不会有任何服务站
There won't be any service stations...
在你发生故障 燃料耗尽 或要喝点什么时提供服务
in case you break down, run out of gas...or need something to drink.
太空探索的挑战之一
One of the challenges of space exploration...
要么是你随身携带的
is either carrying along with you...
你必需的所有的补给 如水 食品 氧气
all the supplies you need... water, food, oxygen...
要么是在途中或目的地寻找某种加工制作方法
or finding some way to manufacture that...en route or at your destination.
我们还没那水平
We're not there yet.
我们还不知道如何去做到
We don't know how to do that yet.
风险之一 如果有什么三长两短
And so one hazard is, if something goes wrong...
你用完了食品 水或保护物品那就坏了
and you run out of food and water and shelter, that's bad.
你将完蛋
You'll die.
每一小口 每一滴水都是宝贵的
Every sip, every drop of water is precious.
太空旅行中不会有淋浴之类的事情的
On a space voyage, there will be no such thing as a shower.
唯一的奢侈品可能就是一块湿布
The only option will likely be a wet cloth.
这确实要改变一天消耗130加仑水
This is quite a change from the 130 gallons of water...
这个美国式的习惯
each American consumes in just one day.
携带的饭菜会和平时吃的差不多
The cuisine onboard would take some getting used to as well.
几天里 你可以吃上新鲜果蔬
For a few days, you can take fresh fruits and fresh vegetables...
如胡萝卜 苹果之类的东西
carrots and apples and things like that.
对于较长的任务 虽然你不得不用上储存食品
For the longer missions, though, you have to have storable foods...
但还好 那东东长时期内是不会变质腐败的
that can, you know, stay for long periods of time...without spoiling and going bad.
然而宇航员同意 忍受无数的风险
And yet astronauts agree that enduring the myriad of risks...
是以很小的代价去亲眼目睹宇宙奇观
is a small price to pay for the chance...to witness the wonder of the cosmos in person.
我知道他们的感受 因为他们报告的情况 如
l know how they felt because they report things like...
你可以抬起自己的手指
well, you could hold up yourfinger...
你可以用自己的拇指挡住地球
and you could block out the Earth with your thumb...
就像给了他们一个全新的视角
and it kind of gave them an entire new perspective...
这个蓝色的弹珠球 地球
of how amazing this little blue marble, the Earth, is...
在这片广袤的太阳系里有多珍贵啊
and how precious it is in this vast solar system.
这经历永远改变了我
That experience changed me forever...
我认为它会改变每一个人
and l think it would change anyone...
有可能在将来都有那样的经历
that could possibly have that experience in the future.
不管怎样 未来航程的长度
However, the length of future voyages...
有可能限定在太空游客力所能及的范围内
might limit the range of experiences...available to space travelers.
我们浩瀚宇宙间的距离出乎想像
Distances in ourvast universe can defy comprehension.
如果我们太阳的大小如一个篮球
lf our Sun were the size of a basketball...
我们的地球就像是一颗豌豆
our Earth would be the size of a pea.
如果将它们放在中央公园里
lf they were placed in Central Park...
那么最近的恒星就是另一个篮球
the nearest starwould be another basketball...
几乎是在5000英里外的夏威夷
almost 5,000 miles away in Hawaii.
你可能要做一次航天任务的一个前提
One of the prerequisites you might have for a space mission...
是你能活着抵达目的地
is that you're alive when you arrive at your destination...
所以必须将你的航天任务压缩到
so you'd want your space missions to be small...
人类的平均寿命里面
compared with the life expectancy of a human being.
现在 那差不多把我们局限在了去行星
And right now, that pretty much limits us to the planets...
还有彗星和小行星
and possibly comets and asteroids...
即使我们包括了那些我们想去拜访的地方
If we include those as places we might visit.
太阳系内行星的荒蛮无情之所
The brutal, scathing landscapes of the solar system's inner planets...
水星 金星
Mercury and Venus...
并不会成为诱人的旅游目的地
do not make for tempting vacation destinations.
金星上的温度超过了华氏900度
Temperatures on Venus can exceed 900 degrees Fahrenheit.
致密的气压
And the crushing air pressure...
相当于淹没在水下3000英尺
is equivalent to being submerged in 3,000 feet of water.
那些旅程全都指向了进一步远离太阳作潜在的探索
That leaves all points further out from the Sun for potential exploration.
然而即使前往我们最近的景点
But even trips to our closest attractions...
也会要用上几个月甚至几年
will still take several months, or even years.
地球与火星的轨道之间的距离约1.39亿英里
About139 million miles separate the orbits of Earth and Mars.
然而 由于各自围绕太阳运转的速度不同
But since each body circles the Sun at different speeds...
彼此之间的距离在不断地变化
the distances, with respect to each other, change continuously.
前往火星的问题在于火星与地球只能排成一线时
The problem with going to Mars is that Mars and the Earth only line up...
约每两年才一次
about once every two years.
以目前的化学推进火箭的技术
With current chemically propelled rocket technology...
2018年从地球飞往红色星球
a flight leaving from Earth for the Red Planet in 2018...
两个靠在太阳一边时
when the two bodies are on the same side of the Sun...
会用上104天的时间 少于4个月
could take 104 days, less than four months.
在呆上40天后
After a forty-day stay...
回程就需要6个月不到的时间
the return trip would require a little more than six months.
也就是打个来回整整一年的工夫
That's an entire year to make one round trip.
然而 若在2031年启程
But a voyage departing in 2031...
到时地球与火星处在太阳的相对位置上
when the Earth and Mars are on the opposite sides of the Sun...
就会需要20个月 将近两年的旅行时间
would demand about twenty months, nearly two years of travel time.
那是远离任何生命线一到两年的时间
That's one to two years away from any lifeline.
彗星 那些超大脏雪球
Comets, those oversized dirty snowballs...
冲到地球很近的地方 足以打一个来回
swoop close enough to Earth to accommodate a round trip...
至少也要几个月
lasting as short as a few months.
找到那些接近太阳的彗星并搭乘它
Find some comet that's on its way into the Sun and ride it.
看着彗星的成长和尾巴的形成
And watch the coma grow and the tail form...
看着太阳 先是慢慢的 然后突然加速
and watch the Sun, first slowly, but then rapidly...
变得越来越大 越来越大
get larger and larger and larger...
你调转屁股 出来了
and you swing around the backside and come out.
那会是太阳系里最有趣的旅行
lt's got to be the most fun tour of the solar system...
你能够赶上的
you can come up with.
存在着危险 因为彗星的粒子
lt'd be dangerous because particles of the comet...
会扬起打在你的脸上等等
would fly up and hit you in the face and things.
所以且不说会先杀死你
So, apart from all that, which would kill you...
那将会是一个有趣的旅行
it would be a fun trip.
一跨出火星轨道
Just beyond the orbit of Mars...
小行星就飞行在从地球几年打来回的范围内
asteroids fly within range of a fewyears' round trip from Earth.
未来的旅行社可能会安排
Future travel agencies might arrange...
极端假期的宇宙版本
cosmic versions of extreme vacations...
着手开发这些小行星独特的环境
by exploiting the unique environments of these miniature planets.
他们将你放上雪橇 把你弹入太空
They put you on a sled and slingshot you into space...
以这样的方式 小行星微弱的引力
in such a way that the weak gravity of the asteroid...
会把你拉入轨道 然而却不会将你再送回来
will hold you in orbit, but won't pull you back down again.
那将是个了不起的搭乘
lt would be a great ride.
火星距离的三倍远的地方
Three times farther away than Mars...
木星的轨道上 是其拥挤的卫星系统
the orbit of Jupiter, with its crowded moon system...
呈现出数十种不同的景观
offers dozens of diverse visions.
它有可能为未来的游客带来诱惑
lt may prove tempting forfuture travelers...
但是 一个往返可能就需要5年的时间
but a round trip could take five years.
土星几乎是木星的两倍远
Saturn is nearly twice as far as Jupiter...
10年旅游的念头可能太过分了
and the thought of decade-long trips might be too much to bear.
然而科技能够分割时间
But there are technologies...
使得参观火星就几天工夫
that can slice the time it takes to visit Mars tojust a few days.
对于人类冒险闯入宇宙深处
For mankind ever to venture into the depths of the cosmos...
尝试沐浴在异域恒星的星光中
endeavor to bathe in the light of an exotic star...
乃至就在我们太阳系的郊区巡游
or evenjust to voyage to the suburbs of our own solar system...
我们需要找到一种非常非常快捷的出游方式
we'll need to find a way to travel much, much faster.
出游最快的方式是什么呢？
What's the fastest we could travel?
科学已经断言没有什么能够跑的
Nothing yet observed by science moves faster...
快过光速 每秒18.6英里
than the speed of light, 186,000 miles per second.
光速是宇宙间的终极速度
The speed of light is the ultimate velocity in the universe.
这是爱因斯坦定下的规矩
lt's Einstein's cop on the block.
光速使你绕地球跑七圈只需一秒钟
The speed of light is so fast that you could go around the Earth...seven times in just one second.
你以光速跳上月球的话
For you to jump to the Moon, at the speed of light...
抵达月球就一秒钟的时间
you could reach the Moon in about one second.
与之相比 以目前的科技则需要三天才能到达那里
Compare that to the three days it takes...to get there with current technology.
问题是我们无法以光速出行
The problem is that we can't travel at the speed of light...
甚至还没有什么能接近它
or really anything even approaching it.
拿我们曾经发送过的最快的东西
Take the fastest thing we have ever sent anywhere...
来问一下 去最近的恒星需要多长的时间
and ask how long will that take to reach the nearest stars.
那需要5万年
That would take 50,000 years.
那是利用现有化学推进技术
And that is using current chemical propulsion...
其最高纪录是时速4万英里
which maxes out at about 40,000 miles per hour...
我们用来让火箭离开地球的能量是一样的
the same power source we use...to lift our rockets off of the planet.
然而要让我们前往火星快上几个月
But getting us to Mars faster than a few months' time...
就需要别的推进方式
would require a different kind of propulsion.
有了一些想法 如何让我们的推进
There are a few ideas for how to propel us...
速度更接近光速
to velocities closer to the speed of light...
能够快到足以
which would be fast enough...
把我们在一天内送达太阳系的任何一个地方
to get us anywhere in the solar system in under a day...
以致在10年内抵达最近的恒星
or even to the nearest stars in less than a decade.
回想一个理论
One such theory echoes...
俗世古老的推进装置:
an ancient earthly propulsion device:
风帆
Wind pushing a sail.
是伟大的天文学家开普勒
lt was Kepler, that great astronomer...
首先在他的笔记中提到
who first wrote down in his notes...
有可能利用风帆扬帆在外太空中
the possibility of using sails to sail in outer space.
来自太阳的光流
Light streaming from the Sun...
酷似外太空中的阵阵凉风
mimics gusts of wind in outer space.
这种太阳风就是彗星接近太阳时创造其尾巴的东西
This solarwind is what creates a comet's tail as it nears the Sun.
可是 阳光是四面八方散开的
However, sunlight scatters in all directions...
与太阳的距离增加一倍
and as the distance from the Sun doubles...
其能量则会减少四倍
its power reduces by a factor of four.
凭借月球的少许帮助
With a little help from the Moon...
就会有一种情况 光可以集中在一个方向
there is a manner in which light could be focused in one direction.
如果我们在月球上有一组激光炮
lf we have a battery of laser cannons on the Moon...
对准太阳帆同步开炮
firing in synchronization at a solar sail...
我们就有可能推进它
we may be able to propel it...
或许可以达到光速的一半
to about perhaps half the speed of light.
现在 激光会在太空中弥散开
Now, lasers do diffuse with space.
比如 我在地球上有一个激光
For example, if l have a laser on the Earth...
射向月球
and l shine it to the Moon...
它不会在月球上产生一个光斑
it does not create a spot on the Moon.
这个光斑在月球上会有5英里宽
The spot is about five miles across on the Moon.
这些风帆无论如何将会很巨大
These sails, however, would be huge.
现在我们谈到了宇航员
Now we're talking about astronauts...
或许要在外太空度过数月
perhaps spending months in outer space...
布置一个数百英里 甚至数千英里宽的风帆
designing a sail hundreds..maybe even thousands of miles across...
轻巧耐用 目的是为了采集月球上的激光炮发出的光
sufficiently light and durable in order to capture light...from a battery of laser beams on the Moon.
不过太阳风帆把太空旅行的目的地
But solar sailing limits space vessels...
局限在了太阳系里
to destinations within our solar system.
回避这个问题 有一个替代方案
One alternative gets around this problem...
就是利用氢 宇宙中最丰富的元素
by tapping into hydrogen...the most abundant element in the universe...
来作为推进能源
as a propulsion source.
我最中意的送我们去恒星的方案
My favorite design to take us to the stars...
就是核聚变喷气发动机
is the ramjet fusion engine.
这种喷气发动机在其正前方有一个巨大的戽斗
The ramjet engine has a gigantic scoop...in the forward direction...
在其在深太空行进时吞下氢气
that gobbles up hydrogen gas as it moves in deep space.
它收集氢气
lt collects the hydrogen gas...
然后像太阳那样将它聚合
and then fuses it just like the Sun...
在其另一端射出巨大的离子流
and shoots out a huge stream of ions out the other end.
理论上看来很棒
And on paper, it looks fantastic.
理论上看来好像核聚变喷气发动机
On paper it looks as if a ramjet fusion engine...
可以永久运行 只是在消耗氢气
could go on forever, simply using up the hydrogen...
外太空里比比皆是的东西
that is found naturally in outer space.
很遗憾 科学家在实验中尚未达到
Unfortunately, scientists have not yet been able to achieve...
对氢核聚变反应的可控能力
a hydrogen fusion reaction capable of propulsion in tests.
然而另一个潜在的能源
But another potential fuel source...
好像是科幻小说中出现的那种
one that seems to come right out of science fiction...
已经在实验室里创造出来了
has already been created in laboratories.
它叫做反物质
lt's called anti-matter...
它与我们所知的一切刚好相反
and it's the opposite of all that we know.
比如 思考一下镜像里的世界
For example, think of the world...on the other side of the looking glass.
就像是刘易斯·卡罗尔的《爱丽斯漫游仙境》
Just like in Lewis Carroll's "Alice in Wonderland"...
我们的物理学家一直在想
we physicists have wondered, is there another universe...
镜子里另一头的宇宙是否是
on the other end of the looking glass...
一个完全倒过来的宇宙
a parity-reversed universe...
在那里左变成了右 而右变成了左了呢？
where left becomes right, right becomes left?
在反宇宙中电荷是反过来的
ln an anti-universe, charges are reversed...
所以正电荷变成了负电荷
so positive charges become negative...
负电荷变成了正电荷
negative charges become positive...
一旦它们相遇就会产生能量爆发
and when they meet, they create a burst of energy.
所以 如果镜子里的另一头是宇宙
So if this universe on the other side of the looking glass...
是反物质构成的
were made out of anti-matter...
我一旦接触到这个宇宙
and l were to touch this other universe...
我就会在能量大爆发中摧毁
l would destroy...
纽约的大部分城区
most of the NewYork City metropolitan area...in a burst of energy.
因此 反物质和物质转换成能量
So the conversion of anti-matter and matter to energy...
是百分之百的高效
is one hundred percent efficient.
这是终极发动机 但还存在一个隐情
lt is the ultimate engine, but there is a catch.
总是隐情不断
There's always a catch.
即使我们能够在实验室里创造出反物质
Even though we can create anti-atoms in the laboratory...
其成本是相当惊人的
the cost is stupendous.
可能让美国破产
lt would bankrupt the United States of America...
才能创造出一茶匙反物质
to create a teaspoon of anti-matter.
不管怎样只需要几克反物质
However, it would only take a few grams of anti-matter...
就能将我们送往火星
to take us to Mars...
或许几茶匙反物质
and perhaps several teaspoons of anti-matter...
就能将我们送往附近的恒星
to take us to the nearby stars.
然而我们只要是去访问遥远的恒星或另一个星系
But for us to evervisit...a distant star or another galaxy...
我们所需要的东西就甚至要比爱丽丝
we need something stranger...
凝视她的镜子所渴求的更为陌生
than even Alice could ever dream of...peering through her looking glass.
科学家孜孜以求推进的方法
Scientists continue the quest for a propulsion method...
把我们不断送入更深的太空
to carry us ever deeper into space.
但是即使达到了光速 也不会让我们走得更远
But even achieving light-speed won't allow us to get very far.
光很快 然而宇宙太大了
Light's fast, but the universe is huge.
所以 即使我们能够搭乘上光束
So, even If we could ride on a beam of light...
如果我们想要穿越星系
If we wanted to cross the galaxy...
他们所做的一切都已经在科幻小说中安排了
the way they do in all the science fiction programs...
将需要10万年的时间
it would take 100,000 years to do it.
即使以光速前往最近的星系
And even at light-speed, traveling to the nearest galaxy...
也需要几百万年
would take several million years.
如果光速是宇宙的速度的极限
And if light-speed is the ultimate speed limit of the universe...
看来我们命中注定限制在了
it seems we are doomed to confinement...
我们的银河系周围了
in our galactic neighborhood.
我们迫切需要的
What we're desperate for...
是对时空结构的一些新的认识
is some new understanding of the fabric of space-time...
能让我们设法弯曲它
that will allow us to somehow warp it...
扭曲它 以便我们能够走捷径
distort it so that you can take shortcuts...
当然 那是他们在《星际迷航》中的情景
and, of course, that's what they do in "Star Trek"...
那时他们打开了他们的翘曲飞行
when they turn on theirwarp drives.
他们想从星系的一面到另外一面去
They want to get from one side of the galaxy to the other...
他们所做的一切就是调用翘曲飞行
all they do is invoke the warp drive...
来弯曲太空组织
that warps the fabric of space...
然后他们就在那里找到了一点捷径
and then they take a little shortcut right there.
他们实际上是在耍手腕
They cheat, basically.
大家都知道爱因斯坦的名言:
Everybody knows Einstein's famous dictum...
你无法超过光速
"You cannot go faster than the speed of light".
可是它有一个脚注
However, there's a footnote to it.
你看 爱因斯坦还是留有余地的
You see, Einstein left open the possibility that you can...
你可以撕裂折叠时空本身的结构
rip, fold the fabric of space and time itself...
这样你实际上获得了一条通行宇宙的捷径
so that you effectively take a shortcut through the universe.
想想地毯
Think of a carpet.
如果你想穿过地毯
lf you want to go across the carpet...
那可是老式的办法
that's the old-fashioned way.
你也可以用上一个套索
You can also get a lasso...
套住地毯另一头的桌子
and lasso a table on the other side of the carpet...
然后将桌子拽向你
and then drag the table toward you...
那样你就将空间折叠在了你的面前
so that you collapse the space in front of you.
简而言之 爱因斯坦说 质量越大
ln a nutshell, Einstein says the bigger the mass...
其对时空的弯曲也就越大
the bigger the bending of space and time.
如果你将极大的能量浓缩到一点上
lf you can concentrate...enormous amounts of energy at a single point...
类似于黑洞或超大星体
comparable to that of a black hole...or a huge, gigantic star...
你实际上在弯曲时空的结构
you are literallywarping the fabric of space and time.
你只要跳到附近的恒星上去了
You simply hop across to the nearby stars.
所以换句话说 你不用真的到那些恒星去
So, in otherwords, you did not really go to the stars...
它们会过来的
the stars came to you...
因为你压缩了你前面的空间
because you are compressing the space in front of you.
需要大量的能量或质量
The massive amount of energy or mass needed...
来创造这样一个弯曲的空间
to create such a warped curvature of space...
似乎令人费解
seems beyond comprehension...
或许超越了人类的能力
and perhaps beyond human capability.
也许有一种选择
There may be an alternative.
物理学家约翰.勃兰登堡在发展一个理论
Physicist John Brandenburg is developing a theory...
其中未来的星际飞船
in which a starship of the future...
可以实现超光速飞行
could achieve faster-than-light travel...
并非通过操控宇宙的大片区域
not by manipulating a vast area of the universe...
而是指操控飞船周围的空间
but rather by manipulating only the area around the starship.
诀窍在于将飞船模仿成一个奇怪的粒子
The trick is to have a starship imitate a curious particle...
当然 迄今为止 还只是理论上
that, so far, only exists in theory.
它叫做超子(超光速粒子)
lt's called a tachyon.
那是能各种旋转的粒子
lt's a particle with a different twist.
光本身的速度是恒定的
Light itself always moves at the same speed.
另一方面超子可以跑得无限快
Tachyons, on the other hand, can go infinitely fast.
它们就是无法慢于光速
They just can't go slower than the speed of light.
它们视光速为自己无法逾越的速度底线
They look at the speed of light...as a lower speed limit that they cannot violate.
如果它们确实存在 超子就能够超过光速
lf they do exist, tachyons can outrun the speed of light...
因为它们具有物理学家承认的假象质量
because they have what physicists recognize...as imaginary mass.
假想值可以在击中网球的旋转中看到
An imaginary value can be visualized...in the spin of a struck tennis ball.
旋转会引起球的弯曲和移动
lts spin can cause it to bend and move...
一定程度上旁观者不可能
in a manner that an observer might not expect to see...
从它开始接触的那点预料到
from its initial point of contact.
同样超子在宇宙间是看不见的
ln the same way, a tachyon is unseen by the universe...
它可以打破速度极限
and can break its speed limits.
勃兰登堡提出
Brandenburg proposes...
用强大的电磁场来改变飞船周围的时空
altering the space-time surrounding a starship...with a powerful electromagnetic field...
这样飞船就能像超子那样穿行太空
so that the ship moves through space like a tachyon.
其动作就像隐形飞机
lt would operate like a stealth aircraft...
隐踪于雷达
invisible to radar, unseen by radar operators.
所以 如果谁能操控飞船周围的时空的话
So, if one can achieve this control...of the space-time around this ship...
那么谁就基本上成了假想的物体了
one can essentially make it an imaginary object.
在技术上 这意味着其速度超过了光
ln a technical way, that means it's moving faster than light.
你基本上是把自己和宇宙断开了
You're basically disconnecting yourself...from the rest of the cosmos.
它可以赋予了游客在一眨眼工夫
lt could grant the traveler the ability...
到宇宙任何地方的能力
to go anywhere in the universe in the blink of an eye...
就好像一下子出现了许多出入口
as if a multitude of doorways suddenly appeared.
你踏入一个大门
A doorway you step into...
然后从楼下的某个地方出来
and then you step out somewhere down the hall...
速度快到好像你根本没有时间去别的地方
so fast that it didn't seem like you had time to move anyplace.
那是一个时空的虚连结
That's an imaginary connection in space-time.
你改变的是你自己 而非时空
And you've changed yourself, not space-time.
没有人知道有多快 乃至飞船会到达哪里
No one may know howfast or even where...such a space vessel could travel.
哪个门进 哪个门出？
Which door to go into? Which door to come out of?
那是个戏法
That's the trick.
然而穿行于宇宙大殿不可能
But voyaging through the hall of the universe isn't possible...
不先克服其基本力之一
without first overcoming one of its fundamental forces...
那就是我们地球对我们的束缚
the one that shackles us to our home planet.
摆脱地球的引力场
Getting away from the Earth's gravitational field...
是我们必须面临的第一关
that's the first thing that we have to do.
十 九 八…
Ten, nine, eight...
七 六…
seven, six...
对于物体挣脱地球的引力…
For an object to break away from Earth's gravitational pull...
二 一
...two, one.
我们已经点火发射了航天局新的…
We have ignition and liftoff of NASA's new...
必须达到时速1.75万英里
...it must achieve a velocity of17,500 miles per hour.
其速度之快 从纽约到洛杉矶
That's fast enough to streak from NewYork to Los Angeles...
不到8分钟
in about eight minutes.
别无他法可以做到
There's no otherway to do it...
除了蛮力 至少到目前是这样
at least that we have now, other than brute force.
虽然理论上的太空电梯
While a theoretical space elevator...
可以攀爬摆脱地球的引力
can climb away from Earth's gravitational pull...
但是火箭必须靠燃烧燃料产生的
a rocket must outrun it with the brute force...
化学爆炸反应的蛮力来挣脱
provided by the explosive chemical reaction of burning fuel.
化学能驱动着今天的火箭发动机
Chemical power is what drives today's rocket engines.
每次你燃烧东西 那就是化学能
Every time you burn something, that's chemical power.
每次点燃火箭发动机
Every time a rocket engine ignites...
那就是化学能
that's chemical power.
每次你发动汽车的发动机
Every time you start your engine in your car...
你都在使用油罐里的化学能
you're using the chemical energy stored in the gasoline.
燃料只能增加飞船有限空间的负担
The fuel alone can burden a space-bound craft...
高达其总重量的九成
with up to ninety percent of its total weight.
如果你带足你所需要的燃料
lf you're carrying all the fuel you'll ever need...
那么已开始燃烧的燃料的大部分作用
then most of the effort of the first-ignited fuel...
是在把未燃烧的燃料送入轨道
is to lift the unburnt fuel into orbit.
这就像试图开车从纽约到洛杉矶
lt'd be like trying to drive from NewYork City to Los Angeles...
拉上一大罐汽油
on one tank of gas.
你就需要有辆油罐车跟着你
Well, you would need a tanker truck behind you.
油罐车消耗的大部分能量
And most of the energy to accelerate the tanker truck...
将只是在搬运油罐车里油
is going in tojust move the fuel that's in the tanker truck.
航天飞机 它的火箭及其所携带的燃料
The space shuttle, its rockets, and the fuel they're carrying...
重量是惊人的400万磅
weigh a staggering four million pounds.
无异于白骨敲打的喷发
And nothing short of a bone-rattling eruption...
可以将它升空 离开地球
could push it up and away from Earth.
啊 格兰特 看来你的长期等待即将结束了
Well, Grant, looks like your long wait is over.
我们祝愿各位一路顺风 圆满成功
We wish you all the best luck in the world, Godspeed...
我们将在两周后迎接你们
and we'll see you back in here in about two weeks.
今天的太空之旅意味着太空游客
Ajourney into space today means that space travelers...
必须搭乘受控的爆炸升空
must ride a controlled detonation into the sky.
无论交通工具有多重 我们都必须产生
Whatever the vehicle weighs, we have to generate...
1.5到2倍的推力
about one and a half to two times that thrust...
以将它离开地表
in order to get it off the surface of the Earth.
要让航天飞机达到速度
To get the space shuttle up to speed...
就需要700万磅的推力
demands seven million pounds of thrust.
要进入那个状态…
To put that into perspective...
如果你能想像我手里握着一个一磅的球
lf you can imagine me...holding a one-pound ball in my hand.
如果在这里拿着它不动
lf l'm holding it here, and l'm holding it steady...
我就要施加一磅的推力给那个球
l am exerting a pound of thrust on that ball.
那么 如果我将它放低 我就明显不用施加一磅的力了
So, if l lower it down, l'm clearly not exerting the one pound.
如果我将它举高 施加的力就不止一磅
lf l pick it up, l'm exerting more than a pound.
这样你必须要比重量多一点的推力
So you have to have a little more thrust...
否则你就到不了位
than you do the weight, obviously, or you won't go anywhere.
火箭的运动可以用一个吹大的气球来说明
How a rocket moves can be illustrated with a blown-up balloon.
这个作用就像发动机喷嘴
This works almost like an engine nozzle.
现在 我拿着它就位
Now, l can hold it in place...
你可以控制它 你可以放开它
and you can control it, you can let it go.
我们要做的是让许多东西
And what we do is, we try to eject as much mass...
随着我们控制通过那个喉咙
through that throat as we can.
由于它后面膨胀了
And as it expands out the back end...
其爆发 或推动的压力
that expansion or that pressure pushing that way...
将交通工具推向那边
pushes the vehicle this way.
当今天的宇航员进入
When today's astronauts climb aboard...
他们的航天飞机的行程时
for theirjourneys on the space shuttle...
他们搭载了巨大的集装箱来装载必需品
they're hitching to giant containers housing that necessary mass.
数百万磅的高可燃氢和氧蓄势待发
Millions of pounds of highly combustible hydrogen and oxygen...wait to be ejected.
只需要一个火花
lt only takes a spark.
主发动机在起飞前6秒钟点火
The main engine starts six seconds before takeoff.
整个飞机晃动不已
The whole shuttle shakes.
感觉就像它要把我撕碎在发射台上一样
lt feels like it wants tojust rip itself out of the launch pad.
奋进号升空
Lift off of Space Shuttle "Endeavour"...
它抖个不停 你会想:"噢 天哪"
lt shudders, and you think, "Oh, my gosh"...
什么鬼力道啊
"that's an awful lot offorce."
约150万磅的推力
About a million and a half pounds of thrust.
梦幻一般
lt's kind of surreal.
就像 不可能是真的吧
lt's like, "This can't really be happening".
这是年复一年一直等待的
lt's something you've been wanting to do...
真真实实的发生了
for years and years, and it's really happening.
就像在驾乘人造地震
lt's like riding a manmade Earthquake.
你花了几百万磅燃料
You've spent several million pounds worth offuel...
来获得前两分钟的飞行
to get to the first two minutes offlight...
然后固体火箭推进器就脱落了
and then the solid rocket boosters come off.
那些东西脱落时就像是火车的残骸
And that's like a train wreck when those things come off.
感觉几乎就像你就是在加速
lt almost feels like you're just accelerating...
越来越快 越来越快
faster and faster and faster...
同时你在烧尽大储罐里所有的燃料
as you burn all the fuel out of the big main tank.
在下来的6分钟里你将加速到
So for the next six minutes, you're accelerating up to a point...
你感觉到3个G
where you're finally feeling about three gs...
重力加速度的3倍
three times the force of gravity of acceleration.
现在几乎就感觉到像有三只大猩猩
And so now it almost feels like there's a big gorilla...
坐在你的胸部
sitting on your chest.
赛车手加速 从时速0到100英里
A drag racerwho accelerates from zero to 100 miles per hour...
不到两秒钟就会感到一个G的重力
in two seconds will feel g forces...
类似于那些宇航员的体验
similar to those experienced by astronauts.
随着飞行器的持续加速
As the vehicle keeps accelerating...
你可以看到速度一点点加速到每秒数千英尺
and you're watching the speed tick by...in thousands offeet per second...
直到达到音速的25倍
until you get to twenty-five times the speed of sound.
然后熄火了 东西都飘了起来
Then there's a cut-off, and then everything's floating...
现在你置身太空了
and nowyou're in space.
所以太空并非遥不可及
So space isn't very far away.
只需要8分30秒就可以到达那里了
lt only takes about eight minutes and thirty seconds to get there.
下一个闯入来世 前往新世界的模式
The next model forventuring into the great beyond...and reaching new worlds...
将以拜访一位老朋友为开端
will begin first with a visit to an old friend.
尽管太空电梯尚未面世
Although not quite yet a space elevator...
但是航天局的返回月球的任务
NASA's mission to return to the Moon...
将建立在以地球轨道作为更远航程的基地的想法上
builds on the idea of Earth orbit as a base forfarthervoyages.
宇航局的星座计划
NASA's Constellation Program...
传奇的阿波罗计划的继承者
a successor to the legendary Apollo Program...
目标是到2020年立足月球
aims to plant boots on the Moon by 2020.
两个单独的火箭构成了该计划的基础
Two separate rockets form the foundation of the plan.
无人驾驶战神5型火箭
The unmanned Ares V rocket...
其高度超过了足球场的长度
towering taller than a football field standing on its end...
将携带月球登陆车 补给
will carry the lunar lander, supplies...
以及地球离轨火箭进入轨道
and an Earth departure rocket into orbit...
在那里等候着宇航员
where it will wait for the astronauts.
战神1型火箭将搭载宇航员的座舱送入轨道
The Ares l rocket will deliver the crew to orbit aboard a capsule.
然后与地球离轨火箭回合
lt then will rendezvous with the Earth departure rocket...
飞往月球
and blast to the Moon.
我们可以将更多的补给
We can take more supplies...
更多的货物带上月球
more commodities to the Moon.
那就是这种串联系统为我们提供的
That's what this tandem system provides for us, instead of Apollo...
而不是阿波罗只能让我们一次就去一 两天时间
which only allowed us to go for one or two days at a time...
就返回了
and then come back.
我们是否找到了一种方法
Will we everfind a way to surpass...
来超越阿波罗计划的大胆成就了呢？
the bold achievements of the Apollo program?
我们穿行广袤的宇宙能否
Will we ever cross the vast expanse of the cosmos...
像越洋去另一个城市旅行那般快捷轻松呢？
as quickly and effortlessly as we travel...to another city or another continent?
我们必须认识到如果我们要作为一个种族生存下去
We must If we are to survive as a people.
如果我们停止探索
lf we stop exploring...
那么历史一再告诫我们
we have learned time and time again throughout history...
那些种族基本上就会走向衰退与消亡
that those societies, basically, tend to wither up and die.
那是我们的职责
lt's a part of what we are...
那是我们对子孙后代的交代
it's a part of what we leave to our children...and their children.
那是我们的天性 那是我们的责任
lt's who we are, and it's what we do.
谢谢观赏
Thanks For Viewing